MUHAMMAD KAHFY NOOR ALWANI

+62-878-6495-9745 | kahfinoor013@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/kahfy-noor/

Portofolio: https://kahfinoor.github.io/Portofolio/

Makassar, Sulawei Selatan, Indonesia

I'm Muhammad Kahfy Noor Alwani, an Undergraduate Student in Computer and Networking Engineering, and an IT enthusiast with experience as a web developer involving the design, development, and maintenance of websites. My ability to implement various programming languages, such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and PHP has allowed me to create attractive and functional interfaces. I also possess skills in using frameworks like Codelgniter, Laravel, and Node.js to enhance the responsiveness and complexity of websites. Additionally, I have delved into Cloud Computing and Virtualization, exploring various features of Google Cloud products such as Compute Engine, App Engine, Cloud Run, and more.

Education

Politeknik Negeri Ujung Pandang, Makassar, Sulawesi Selatan, Indonesia

Sep 2021 - Present

Teknik Komputer dan Jaringan

Mata Kuliah Relevan:

 Desain & Pemrograman Web, Integrasi Data, Rekayasa Perangkat Lunak, Basis Data, Struktur Data, Algoritma dan Pemrograman, Desain Algoritma, Aplikasi Mobile.

SMKS Kartika XX-1 Makassar, Makassar, Sulawesi Selatan, Indonesia

Jul 2018 - May 2021

Rekayasa Perangkat Lunak

Mata Pelajaran Relevan:

 Pemrograman Web, Pemrograman Berorientasi Objek, Pemodelan Perangkat Lunak, Basis Data, Aplikasi Mobile.

Experiences

Cloud Computing, Makassar, Sulawesi Selatan, Indonesia

Feb 2024 – Jul 2024

Bangkit Academy by Google, Gojek, Tokopedia, & Traveloka

- Deploying and managing virtual machines, storage solutions, and network configurations on GCP to meet the infrastructure needs of teams.
- Utilizing GCP services like Google App Engine, Cloud Functions, and Cloud Run to develop, manage, and scale applications without the complexities of maintaining the underlying infrastructure.
- Implementing and managing various GCP data storage solutions, including Cloud Storage, Firestore, Cloud SQL, and Bigtable, to ensure efficient data management and accessibility.
- Deploying trained machine learning models to GCP services such as AI Platform or TensorFlow Serving to make them accessible for inference.
- Designing and implementing RESTful API endpoints that allow mobile developers to send requests to the machine learning model and receive predictions or results. This involves using services like Cloud Endpoints, API Gateway, or custom server implementations.

Marketing & Beta Tester, Makassar, Sulawesi Selatan, Indonesia

May 2021 - Aug 2021

Saudagar Teknologi ID

- Conduct a trial of the application that will be presented to MSMEs.
- Configure the data sets that it can be used in the Application.
- Setting up data sets for MSMEs.
- Application socialization for customers.

Organization

Himpunan Mahasiswa Teknik Informatika dan Komputer

Feb 2024 – Present

Member of Education Department (Programming Subdivision)

 Organized discussions and training sessions and taught students to familiarize them with the field of programming.

Computer And Network Community (CNC)

Sep 2023 – May 2024

Head of Development and Knowledge Division (Ketua 1 Bidang Internal)

- Leading 6 knowledge divisions (Programming, Cyber Security, Graphic Design, Internet of Things, Networking, and Machine Learning) and 1 development division (Coaching Division).
- Planning teaching and training sessions related to informatics and computer technology.
- Mentoring students in training activities and competitions.

Computer And Network Community (CNC)

Sep 2022 – May 2023

Member of Programming Division

• Organizing discussions about programming and conducting training sessions.

Project

•	Indoor Air Quality Monitoring System with IoT	Sep 2023 – Jan 2024
•	Mobile Cashier & Finance Application – Shurya Snack	Oct 2023 – Jan 2024
•	Website Al-Quran: Ayat and Tafsir with API	Apr 2023 – May 2023
•	API Football Maniacs	Mar 2023 – Jul 2023
•	Web Apps for SME Inventory Management – UKM Bahasa PNUP	Mar 2023 – Jul 2023
•	Motorcycle Spare Parts Web Cashier	Sep 2023 – Des 2023

Skills

- Hard Skill: Web Development, HTML, CSS, PHP, Javascript, Java, Python, SQL, Node.js, Figma.
- Soft Skill: Adaptability, Critical Thinking, Problem Solving, disciplined, and collaborate in a team.

Training and Certification

- Memulai Dasar Pemrograman untuk Menjadi Pengembang Software (Dicoding Indonesia) Feb 2024
- Pengenalan ke Logika Pemrograman (Dicoding Indonesia) Feb 2024
- Belajar Dasar Git dengan GitHub (Dicoding Indonesia) Feb 2024
- Belajar Dasar Pemrograman Web (Dicoding Indonesia) Mar 2024
- Belajar Membuat Aplikasi Back-End untuk Pemula dengan Google Cloud (Dicoding Indonesia) Mar 2024
- Belajar Membuat Aplikasi Back-End untuk Pemula (Dicoding Indonesia) May 2024
- Belajar Dasar Pemrograman JavaScript (Dicoding Indonesia) May 2024
- Belajar Dasar-Dasar DevOps (Dicoding Indonesia) May 2024
- Belajar Dasar Structured Query Language (SQL) (Dicoding Indonesia) May 2024
- Belajar Dasar Google Cloud (Dicoding Indonesia) May 2024
- Memulai Pemrograman dengan Dart (Dicoding Indonesia) May 2024
- Python Fundamental (Aguna Course) Jun 2024